<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>A declaration of the commanders and other officers of Colonell Humfrey's regiment, in vindication of themselves from these aspertions and scandals cast upon them, of plotting and fomenting discontents, and obstructing the disbanding of supernumeraries. Imprimatur. Gil. Mabbot.</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1648</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 4 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A82129</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing D651</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E425_14</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R204555</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99864033</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99864033</idno>
            <idno type="VID">116252</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A82129)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 116252)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 67:E425[14])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>A declaration of the commanders and other officers of Colonell Humfrey's regiment, in vindication of themselves from these aspertions and scandals cast upon them, of plotting and fomenting discontents, and obstructing the disbanding of supernumeraries. Imprimatur. Gil. Mabbot.</title>
                  <author>Humfrey, John, Colonel.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 5, [1] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Francis Tyton at the sign of the three Daggers neare the Inner-Temple-Gate in Fleet-Street,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1648.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Signed at end: Colonell Iohn Humfrey [and 9 others].</note>
                  <note>In this edition, the title page does not have a border.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Feb: 3d 1647"; the 8 in imprint date crossed out.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Humfrey, John, --  Colonel --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Military offenses --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2009-02</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-04</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-06</date>
            <label>Megan Marion</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:116252:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 1 -->
            <p>A DECLARATION OF THE Commanders and other Officers OF Colonell HUMFREY'S Regiment, <hi>IN</hi> Vindication of Themſelves from theſe Aſpertions and Scandals caſt upon them, OF Plotting and Fomenting Diſcontents, and obſtructing the Disbanding of <hi>Supernumeraries.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>Imprimatur. <hi>Gil. Mabbot.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>LONDON,</hi> Printed for <hi>Francis Tyton</hi> at the ſign of the three Daggers neare the Inner-Temple-Gate in Fleet-Street, 1648.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:116252:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:116252:2"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 2 -->
            <head>A DECLARATION Of the Commanders and other Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers of Colonell HUMFREY'S Re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>giment, in Vindication of themſelves from theſe aſpertions and Scandals caſt upon them, Of plotting and fomenting diſcontents, and obſtructing the Disbanding of <hi>Supernumeraries.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">A</seg>Ccuſed Innocencie may crave ſo much liberty as to ſpeak for it ſelfe, and we hope a juſt Vindication of our late pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceedings is both convenient and neceſſary. Were not our Enemies pow<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>erfull, and the accuſations guided over with
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:116252:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->pretended truth, wee had not appeared in publique; but things falling out as they doe in the fomicture of time, our expecta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tions being raiſed for a better conſtruction of our actions our ſilence had been our ſins, and wee juſtly culpable of ſo groſſe a neglect.</p>
            <p>We therefore in behalfe of our ſelves and Regiment declare as followeth.</p>
            <p n="1">I. Whereas wee underſtand that divers ſug<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>geſtions of an high nature to the Honoura<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ble Committee of Lords and Commons at <hi>Darby</hi>-Houſe have been tranſmitred againſt us, and from them to his Excellency Sir <hi>Thomas Fairfax,</hi> of obſtructing the buſineſſe of disbanding, as if wee had plotted a com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bination to the fomenting an ill ſpirit a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mongſt our Souldiers. Wee in the ſincerity of our hearts affirme to the World our ready ſubmiſſion to the Authority of Parliament, and Commands of his Excellency. Wee were not ſo unwiſe, having by the bleſſing of God ſo many yeares with all humble ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>jection
<pb n="3" facs="tcp:116252:3"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 3 -->owned the Commands of the State, now at one Exit to ſtaine the honour of that faithfulneſſe with a non-obedience.</p>
            <p n="2">II. Although wee heare of a diſcontented party, men who love to fiſh in troubled wa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, yet as formerly they diſſented from the Army and us in our concurrance with it, ſo none can remonſtrate our diſlike of their proceedings, though neighbouring to us, and that wee are ſo farre from entertaining their deſigne, which if it had been mentio<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ned to us, they ſhould have had nothing but diſcovery and oppoſition from us, and this our laſt Summers actions ſufficiently taught them as the Parliaments Call gave both edge and action to our ſwords, ſo we ſhall willingly ſheathe them at their com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand, notwithſtanding any invitation to the contrary.</p>
            <p n="3">III. That although ſome diſſatisfaction hath
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:116252:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 4 -->met us in the way of disbanding (fire being ſtruck ſuppoſing us a tynder, thereby to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>duce us to aſhes) yet the Eagle ſtoopes not to Flies, and ſuch rebbes ſhall not turne us out of the way of our obedience, by which we ſhall ſerve the publique, which is our maine end, and fruſtrate ſome ends of our contriving Enemies, though it may be ad<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vantagious to them in their private Inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſts.</p>
            <p n="4">IV. Wee are in a ready way of disdanding, our Accounts are ſtating, Orders have been and ſhall be obſerved to the very laſt, and we hope 'twill not bee long ere the worke be finiſhed, Peace being brought home up<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on the wings of Victory, and 'tis one com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fort to have a ſhare in that Peace, in the ob<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taining of which God hath been pleaſed to make uſe of our bloud and labour. If ever the Clowds gather again, and that ſpirit be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gins to worke which we have now laid, or a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny other in oppoſition of the Parliaments Authority, and his Excellencies Commands,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:116252:4"/>
               <!-- PDF PAGE 4 -->though disbanded, yet upon a call from the Parliament we ſhall willingly engage again, being very ambitious of the houour to bee ſtiled the Faithfull Servants of our Engliſh Parliament.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>
                  <date>
                     <hi>Ianuary</hi> 30. 1647.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>
                  <list>
                     <item>Colonell <hi>Iohn Humfery.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Liev. Col. <hi>Iohn Blackmore.</hi>
                     </item>
                     <item>Major <hi>VVilliam Piggit.</hi>
                        <list>
                           <head>Captaines</head>
                           <item>
                              <hi>VVilliam Browne.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Anth. Gardner.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Ionathan Humfrey.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Edward Tyſon.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Anth. Basket.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>Tho. Prichet.</hi>
                           </item>
                           <item>
                              <hi>VVilliam Iones.</hi>
                           </item>
                        </list>
                     </item>
                  </list>
               </signed>
            </closer>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
